#Encodergasm Presents
～
（エド）にゃあ
あうう
This was the most special of the special.
（ジェット）これはな
取っておきの取っておき
It was an emergency ration for true emergencies...
最後の最後ってときのために
取っておいた―
...that was saved for the last of the last resorts.
非常用の非常食だったんだ
All I'm asking is who ate this.
そいつを食っちまったのは
誰だって聞いてんだよ
Grudges over food sure are scary.
（スパイク）食いもんの恨みは
おっかねえなあ
Spike, by perchance, was it you?
（ジェット）
スパイク まさか お前が…
（スパイク）俺が犯人なら―
If I was the culprit, I wouldn't leave the empty box lying around like that.
食った後の空き箱を
そのままにしといたりしない
Ed is hungry.
エド 腹 減ったー
Maybe you ate it yourself, but are pretending...
（フェイ）自分で食べといて
空き箱が見つかったから―
...to be upset because we found the empty box?
怒ってるふりしてんじゃないの？
What?!
なにい？
We haven't had anything to eat for two whole days!!
丸２日も食べるもんがないのよ
こういうのを非常事態って
言うんじゃないの？
Don't you call a situation like this an emergency?!
焼きビーフンとか食いてえなあ
I wanna eat stuff like fried beefun noodles...
We're outta gas!  We can't do anything about it!
（ジェット）
ガス欠なんだ　しょうがねえだろ
このまま もう少し我慢してれば
慣性の法則でエウロパに着くんだよ
If you could hold out like this a bit longer...
...we'll reach Europa soon thanks to inertia.
Tummy's caving in!
ぺこぺこー
（フェイ）
その元気が推進力に使えればね
If only we could use that energy to propel ourselves...
You keep mouthing off like that and I'll toss you out into absolute zero.
（ジェット）
つまんないことばっか言ってると
絶対零度に放り出すぞ
And a stir-fry of liver and chives would be good, too...
レバニラ炒めなんかもいいな
（フェイ）いい話ね
Sounds good.
こんな所で
ふらふら漂ってるよりマシだわ
At least it's better than aimlessly floating around this place.
（スパイク）あーあ
That was some collision...
（フェイ）派手にぶつけたわね
Hey!  Can you hear me?  Answer me!  Hey!!
おい 聞こえるか？
応答しろ！ おい
Isn't this...
これって
当て逃げってやつじゃない？
...a hit-and-run?!
This is bad!  The shock from that collision changed our trajectory!
いかん！さっきのショックで軌道が
What did what to who?
何がどうしたって？
What's going on?!
どうなってんのよ
Huh?
ありゃ？
Wow...  Where is this place?
うわ！ どこ？ ここ　田舎ー
This is so uncivilized!
I don't think that's our problem...
いや そういう問題じゃ…
We have to start by checking the ship.
（ジェット）とりあえず
機体をチェックしないとな
Can you go get some food?
お前は食料でも調達して…
あっ ああ うう…
What?
何だ？
うっ 急に差し込み
I suddenly feel... a stabbing pain...
What are you trying to pull?
（ジェット）何のまねだ？
んお！ 賞味期限が１年も過ぎてる
This expired a year ago...
I'm glad I didn't eat it.
よかった　食わないで
フフ ざまあみろ
天罰だな　フフフフフフ
Serves you right.  This is divine retribution!
フフ ざまあみろ
天罰だな　フフフフフフ
（ジェット）やるか
Let's get to it...
（ジェット･スパイク）
あー あー あー
Whatcha gonna do?
（スパイク）どうするよ？
（ジェット）うーん
Ed will help, too!
（エド）エドもやるー
（ジェット）んん？
We're fine here, so go outside and find us some food.
ここは いいから　外へ行って
なんか食いもんでも探してこい
Okay!
（エド）はーい！
Gotta wear my socks...
（エド）靴下 履いて
お出掛け お出掛けー えへへー
...to go out, to go out...
んにゃ にゃにゃ にゃにゃ
もーう
Nothing here...
なんもないねー
（エド）みゃあ？
ああー！ 当て逃げの船だー
It's that hit-and-run ship!
Wait, wait!
待て 待てー　待て 待てー
Wait, wait!!
Wait, wait!!!
待て 待てー　うん？
匂い
Smell...
Smell... food...
食べ物の匂い
あー！ 食べ物ー！
FOOD!
～
Gimme!
（エド）ちょうだーい
1,000 woolongs each, including tax.
税込みで一つ 1000ウーロン
現金のみだ
Cash only.  No money cards or cash cards allowed.
マネーカードも
キャッシュカードも許さん
I don't have money.
お金ないよ
ちっ とっとと帰んな 小僧
Then hurry home, kid.
Can I have one?
（コフィ）一つ ちょうだい
1,000 woolongs each.  Cash only.  Cards are...
一つ 1000ウーロン
現金のみだ　カードは…
Kid, no use staring.
小僧 見てても駄目だぞ
If you want food, go someplace like the town.
食いもんが欲しけりゃ
町にでも行くんだな
ウフ　釣りは いらないわ
I don't need change.
In exchange...
その代わり
この男を見かけたら連絡ちょうだい
If you see this man, gimme a call.
Thanks!
よろしく
Excuse us.
（警官１）ちょっと 失礼
（警官２）
荷物をチェックさせてもらうぞ
We would like to check your baggage.
Something wrong?
（コフィ）何か事件でも？
Apparently, a broker on the wanted list for...
（警官１）指名手配中の
違法キノコのブローカーが―
...illegal mushroom sales made a getaway to this town.
この町に逃げ込んだらしいんでね
What a coincidence.
偶然ね
あたしも その賞金首を追ってるの
I'm after that bounty as well.
A cowboy?
カウボーイか？
We're gonna check out your trunk.
トランクも見せてもらうぞ
Go ahead, feel free.
どうぞ ご自由に
（警官２）おおっ！
（コフィ）えっ？
（警官１）え？
（警官２）おいっ
Hey!
（コフィ）ああっ！
（警官１）こら！
All right!  FREEZE!
（警官２）動くな！
（コフィ）ちょ ちょっと ちょっと
Now, wait a minute...
All right, stay still...
ようし そのまま―
- I don't know anything about this!
- Turn around!  Hands on the ground!
後ろを向いて
地面に手をつけ！
（コフィ）
知らないわよ こんなの
（コフィ）何すんのよ！
- What are you doing?!
- Now put your hands on the ground!
（警官２）ほら 早くしろ
（警官１）地面に手をつけ！
（コフィ）何すんのよ！
（警官２）ほら 早くしろ
（警官１）地面に手をつけ！
（コフィ）
気安く触んないでよ！
（警官２）ほら 早くしろ
（警官１）地面に手をつけ！
- Let go of me!
- HURRY UP!
（コフィ）
気安く触んないでよ！
（警官２）抵抗をするな！
（警官１）早くしろ！
（コフィ）
気安く触んないでよ！
（警官２）抵抗をするな！
（警官１）早くしろ！
Food, food, do you have any?
（エド）食べ物 食べ物
ありますかー？
Oh, you don't?  Oh, you do?
ないですかー？
あーりまーすかー？
Boy, am I hungry...
腹 減ったねえ
やあ？
（ドミノ）うん うん ん？
あーあー…
Meanie!
ひどーい！
What?
おお 何じゃ？
Gimme!
（エド）ちょうだい
なんか ちょうだーい
Gimme something!
Dammit, stop hanging all over me!
ええい もう まとわりつくな
HEY!
（シャフト）へーい！
（ドミノ）あ？
へへっ まさか俺を忘れたとは
言わさんぜい ドミノ！
I won't let you tell me you forgot who I am, Domino!
はて
Let's see...
Come on!  Remember, dammit!
（シャフト）こら！ 思い出せ
お前からキノコを買った
シャフト兄弟の弟だ！
I'm the younger of the Shaft brothers that bought mushrooms from you!
I really can't recall...
本当 思い出せんが
You do want to know why I drag an empty coffin around like this, don't you?
俺が なぜ―
空の棺おけを引きずって歩いてるか
知りたいだろ？
フフフ　それはなあ―
It's because...
...I'm going to go home after putting your corpse inside...
この中にお前の死体を入れて
持って帰る…
Pieces...  All in pieces!
ばらばら ばーらー
What was what to who?
（ドミノ）何が どうしたって？
くうっ 俺の兄貴は
お前から買ったキノコを食って―
My big bro ate a mushroom he bought from you...
...and laughed and laughed, and twisted his intestines to death!
笑って笑って腸捻転で死んだ！
A happy way to die.
幸せな死に方じゃ
にゃははー
Shut up!
やかあしい！ これというのも
みんな お前のせいだ
Speaking of which, it's all your fault!
That's what I call an unjust resentment!
そりゃ 逆恨みってやつじゃ
Ed is hungry, too!
エドも おなか減った
ちい これでも食らえい！
Take THIS!
どわーあ！
（シャフト）んやー 待て
この野郎ー！ ちきしょー
Wait, you bastard!  Dammit!
Food!
（エド）食べ物だ
Aah!  Don't, Ein!  We have to share!
ああー 駄目だよ アイン
みんなで分けるんだよ
（しゃっくり）
Ein?
アイン？
Bad mushroom?
やばキノコ？
マジ？
This for real?
Delicious!
デリーシャス
フフ まさか
こんなことが あるわけないよな
This really can't be happening.
Really...
まさかな　全く
そんなはず ないよ
This really has no way of happening.
（鼻歌）
にゃー
（フェイ）うーん
（しゃっくり）
（ジェット）フッフッフフフー
Hey...  You know, the world really is a great place...
本当 世界って素晴らしいなあ
ヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッ
Did I just say something?
俺 今 なんか言ったっけ？
Hey, mister.
なあ 旦那
こいつは天国への階段だぜ
分かってんのかい？
This is a stairway to heaven.  You know that, right?
An obnoxious little frog...
うるさいカエルだぜ
I don't care anymore.  I warned you!
（カエル）
知らねえぜ　忠告したからな
Yeah, yeah, that's it.
（ジェット）
そうそう そうなんだよ
俺は世界の秘密が分ーったんだよ
ヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッヘッ
I now know the secrets of the universe.
By the way...
ところで―
...who was I?
俺って誰だっけ？
So these mushrooms are inedible after all...
やっぱり食べられないね キノコ
So, as you can tell, it's time for another episode of BIG SHOT!
（パンチ）さあて 毎度おなじみ
ビッグショットの時間だ
We'll introduce you to more and more bounties this week!
（ジュディ）今週も どんどん
賞金首を紹介していくわよ
So, batting first for us today...
さあて
本日のトップバッターは？
（パンチ）
この男 ドミノ･ウォーカー
...is this man, Domino Walker.
He's currently wanted for selling illegal mushrooms.
違法キノコの売買で
指名手配中なんだって
（エド）
にゃあ？ さっきのおっさん！
The bounty is a conservative 1.2 mil.
That's the guy we just saw!
That's cowgirl, Ein.
カウガールだよ アイン
We earn money, and buy food!
お金を稼いで ご飯を買うんだよ
Ein, you're a cow-woofwoof!
アインは カウわんわんだよ
ひひい
Here we go!
行きますよー
１ ２ ５ ４ こーんにちはー！
One!
Two!
Five!
Four!
Hello!
ふーう
Hey, don't underestimate the police!
（警官１）
おい！ 警察をなめるなよ
I really don't know anything!
本当に知らないんだって
Then why did you have a strange kid and a dog in the trunk of your car?!
どうして知らない子供と犬が
トランクの中に入ってるんだよ？
Hello...  Yes?
はい もしもし
Oh, it's you, Sally.  Really...  You're so hopeless...
サリーか　しょうがないな 本当
I told you so many times not to call me at work...
あれほど職場には
電話するなって言ったのに
And?  Yeah yeah, and that's it?
（警官１）うんうん で？
ああ それだけ？
I mean, I didn't mean it THAT way when I said "that's it?"...
いやあ それだけって
そういう意味じゃなくって…
Yeah, yeah, like that.  I love you, Sally.
そうそう そうだよ
Got it.  Tonight at 7 it is.  Bye-bye!
分かったよ
じゃあ 今夜７時ね　バイバイ
HEY!
（警官１）おおい！
What's wrong, young'un?  Lookin' like that...
（アントニオ）どうした？ 若いの
その面
Did your woman run off without you?
（カルロス）
女にでも逃げられたのかの？
What to say...
（ジョビン）なんとのう
None of your business, old geezers.
ちっ 余計なお世話だ
じじいどもが
（シャフト）んっ？
ぬおっ
んぐーっ！
Oh, man... that's for eating all at once.
あーあー 一気に食うからじゃ
They say when you're in a hurry, go around.
急がば回れって言うじゃろが
Is that right?
（ジョビン）そうかのう
（シャフト）うっ ううー
He's not here...
（エド）んにゃー？
Aah!  That hit-and-run ship!
あーっ 当て逃げの船だ！
（ドミノ）オホホホホ
I'm sure they never even dreamed that I was raising these in here.
まさか この中で栽培しているとは
夢にも思うまいて
んー こりゃ駄目と
This one's bad.
Well, making an emergency landing here was the only miscalculation I had.
ま ここに不時着したことだけは
計算外だったが…
Were you surprised?
びっくりした？
I was.
（ドミノ）した
イヒヒ
What the hell are you guys?
誰なんだ？ お前たちは
Why are you here?
なんで ここにいるの？
That's my line!
そりゃ こっちのせりふじゃ
大体どうやって この中に？
How did you get in here in the first place?
Is that so?!
The door was open.
（エド）ドア 開いてたよ
（ドミノ）なんとっ！
Culprit of the hit-and-run, prepare to get arrested!
当て逃げ犯人さん
お縄をちょうだい
Stink bug gas!
カメムシガース
のわっ！
（せき）
Wait, wait, wait!
この俺から逃げられると思うなよ！
Don't think that you can get away from me!
Don't get in my way!
あたしの邪魔 すんじゃないの！
Ein!  Growl!
こっ こら！ 離さんか
C-Come on!  Let go of me!
～
BOO!
にゃーっ！
Gotcha!
（エド）捕まえたー！
（ドミノ）ま 待て！
W-Wait...
T-These mushrooms are worth 100,000 each.
こ このキノコは一つ10万はする
Let me go, and I'll give them to you.
これと引き換えに私を見逃せ
Why?
なんで？
Think about which one is worth more.
どっちが得か よく考えてみろ
I dunno.
（エド）分かんにゃい
A-Are you an idiot?!
ば ばかか！ お前は
エヘヘヘヘ
Take the mushrooms!
キノコ 持ってけ！
Okay!
はーい！
えへへー うわー あははーい
Thanks.
Oh, it's no problem.
んああー
Yahoo!  Dinner!  Mushroom!
（エド）
やーほー ご飯！ キノコー
100,000 each?  Really?
（フェイ）
一つ 10万だって？ マジ？
That sure would make some money.
確かに すごい金額になるな
These are real?
本物なの？ これ
Excuse me.
（警官３）ちょっと 失礼
（ジェット）うん？
I'm with the police.
警察の者だ
I want to ask a few questions about Domino, an illegal mushroom dealer.
違法キノコを売買してる―
ドミノって男について
聞きたいんだが
Unfortunately, we have no clue.
あいにくですが
心当たりはないですね
I'm so sorry we can't be of any help.
お力になれなくて残念ですわ
Ed knows who that...  MMF!
エド その人… でおっ
アハハハハ
Don't mind her...
気になさらないで
引き換えれば… うう
In exchange, I got...  MMGH!
アハハハ 全く
She's a troublesome kid...
Really...
しょうがない子で
うう うーん… んんっ？
（ジェット･フェイ）ひっ！
ちょっと 君！
Excuse me, sir.
They're okay.
ＯＫです
He must really like shitake mushrooms.
よっぽど好きなんですね
シイタケが
Well, sorry to bother you.
（警官３）じゃ お邪魔しました
Here's dinner.
（ジェット）ほら 飯だ
What's the menu?
（スパイク）メニューは？
Shitake stir-fry, shitake stew, shitake salad, and a shitake dessert.
（ジェット）
シイタケの炒め物と
シイタケの煮物と―
シイタケのサラダと
デザートのシイタケだ
Yaaaaaay!
わーい！
“わーい”って これで何日目よ
Again?  How many days has it been?
No...  I can't eat anymore.
駄目だ　もう食えねえ
Quit complaining, and be thankful that we can even eat!
（ジェット）つべこべ言ってないで
食えるだけ ありがたいと思え
Thankful!
（エド）ありがたーい
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
A videotape that was delivered to the Bebop with no return address.
（ジェット）
ビバップ号に届けられた
差出人不明のビデオテープ
Because we wanted to view the tape, things took a turn for the unexpected.
それを見ようとしたときに
事態は意外な方向へと発展する
No, actually it doesn't go anywhere.
いや 正確には発展しない
At first glance, the story is pointless...
この一見
無意味なストーリーと―
...the actions are on a small scale...
一見 スケールの小さい
アクションと―
...and the ending is forced...
一見 強引な結末に
君は何を感じるか
...but what will you get out of it all?
Next episode: Speak Like a Child.
次回「スピーク･
ライク･ア･チャイルド」
At first glance, it's interesting.
必見　面白いぞ